<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fostering workplace camaraderie</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/fostering-workplace-camaraderie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/fostering-workplace-camaraderie/</guid>
      <description>Socializing is part of human nature, historically. In an earlier post I have talked about the &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; of working. The evolution of work can be divided into three stages: Work, Job, and Career. Initially, as humans transitioned from nomadic hunter-gatherers to agrarian societies, collective tasks and labor hierarchies emerged, transforming the nature of work. In recent centuries, the concept of a &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo; developed, characterized by the professional image and the need for basic qualifications to operate machinery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to be</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/where-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/where-to-be/</guid>
      <description>We cannot choose the first city we live in. Wherever we are born usually becomes our home. I won&amp;rsquo;t mention names, but there are some cities where one is lucky to be born in, whereas there are some other cities where you curse for living in there. It&amp;rsquo;s a matter of probability and not under your control.
What is possible, though, is to move to another city or country in the later years of the life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning if it makes sense</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/questioning-if-it-makes-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/questioning-if-it-makes-sense/</guid>
      <description>I have written before my thoughts about the point of living, benefits of the self-reflection, and some other topics. Those topics come out of questioning things. Questioning and reflecting on our thoughts, actions, beliefs, observations do help us to differentiate meaningful from meaningless, the true value from the false illusion.
The repetition turns the uncomfortable and easy-to-forget things into a habit. Questioning things is not an exception. I believe one should spend on a daily basis at least 15-30 minutes to think about a topic of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to writing, hopefully this time more often</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/back-to-writing-hopefully-this-time-more-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/back-to-writing-hopefully-this-time-more-often/</guid>
      <description>I have not written a blog post since long time. Actually the previous post was written on 22.06.2023. That does not mean I have not written anything though. In the meantime, I have published few posts on Linkedin, mostly on the communication of my weekend hustles, certificate achievements, and sometimes commenting on the posts I have read online.
I also have written quite a lot at my work as a Product Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and Candor: Empowering Employees with Confidence and Trust</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re all grown-up professionals working in organizations to contribute to the success of it and advance our careers. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve undoubtedly experienced obstacles and opportunities. But what keeps us going strong is the sense of togetherness, the spirit of camaraderie, the feeling that we&amp;rsquo;re in it together, fighting the good fight, and celebrating our wins as a team. And you know what? It all boils down to one crucial thing: transparency and candor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting the Way of Zen</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-the-way-of-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-the-way-of-zen/</guid>
      <description>sumi-e painting
Intensity and dynamics of life is changing intermittently. Making plans for the future, describing the things based on the bias of past, and &amp;ldquo;trying&amp;rdquo; to influence the now brings us the frustration of &amp;ldquo;the complexity of ourselves&amp;rdquo;. Alan Watts, in his book &amp;ldquo;The Way of Zen&amp;rdquo;, uses the Thermostat Analogy to explain this frustration.
 The system can be paralyzed in yet another way. Every feedback system needs a margin of “lag” or error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
