<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product-Management on Hido</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/product-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product-Management on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/product-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Psychology of Remote Working and 16 tips to make it work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote working will more likely stay in long term. If not hundred percent, it will definitely push many companies to adopt hybrid model. With the COVID hit, tens of millions of people had to move their workplaces to their living places, to their homes. In multiple studies (mostly by management consulting companies) it is estimated that more than 20 to 25 percent of the workforce could work three to five days a week remotely. Obviously, the remote work at the moment is possible for only the people whose work does not require physical output. There are many dimensions impacted by workforce going remote, such as counter-urbanization, &amp;ldquo;to-go&amp;rdquo; delivery vs. restaurants, commercial real-estate and so on. These are all business-side changes, however there is as well a direct impact of remote working on human psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specializing at becoming a generalist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always had this feeling that I was not good at anything. What I mean is being really good at something, being an expert, master or shihan of it. People who are experts in a specific field have always been target of my appreciation. At the same time, I feel like knowing and being capable at doing various things as well is very attractive, something I &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflect about myself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Innovation, being a critical competitive advantage, is the creative combination of various kinds of knowledge. To bring up innovation, the breadth of the knowledge and expertise base should be large enough. On top of that, these compounds should have a bonding feature which that is a general applicable type within the various shapes and sizes of input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the &#34;why&#34; of working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human beings have been working since quite a long time. Even our primate ancestors worked tools out for hunting of different stones and other materials taken from the nature. So, it should not be such a new concept to reflect upon, thus let&amp;rsquo;s try it. We can put the development of working into three phases: 1) Work, 2) Job, 3) Career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once humans shifted from hunter-gatherer nomad bands into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/&#34;&gt;agrarian settlements&lt;/a&gt;, the design of work changed as well. It was the first time some collective tasks formed and hierarchies of labor emerged, thanks to private property. For quite a long time this work modus operandi continued. Only in the last couple of centuries the idea of &amp;ldquo;job&amp;rdquo; showed up. The main differentiating characteristic of job from work is the professional image. If it was only physical labor that was needed before, now we have a job where we can manage some machinery, which requires a basic qualification we need to amass. Yet very infant, the &amp;ldquo;career&amp;rdquo; concept is what we are living now with. People are not working just to earn money anymore, but rather as well improve their qualifications to move to the next step of their professional growth ladder. Thus the organisations have more difficulty to get their employees stick with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey on managing a product and lessons learned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journey-on-managing-a-product-and-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journey-on-managing-a-product-and-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a very weird dream yesterday. Inside the dream I was still in bed trying to sleep, but there were some numbers and charts flying around and screaming to me. It sounds more of a nightmare, I know. It reminds of the book, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3qL2R13&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Gene, Kevin and George. However, it was not like they were mad at me, but they were asking for more attention. For a moment I could understand them and put them in order for the new realm to reflect itself as a picture. At that moment I was in peace. Then out of nowhere it felt like there is an earthquake, the scene was shaking non-stop and the numbers and charts were gone. I woke up and realised it was my wristband alarm that was on. &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/18/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Every morning&lt;/a&gt; at 5:30 it triggers me to crawl out of bed and start the day with morning routines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
