<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feeling lazy today and it&#39;s fine</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to get this article published on Monday, but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish it before midnight. Instead I just read some articles, listened to some discussions on ClubHouse and slowly started writing. It&amp;rsquo;s not very usual for me in last half a year to take things easy and become lazy whenever I feel like it. That&amp;rsquo;s when questioning kicked in. Why is laziness seen as evil?! Is it really a bad thing to be lazy?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Intermittent Fasting to starve diseases and to feed Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/exploiting-intermittent-fasting-to-starve-diseases-and-to-feed-autophagy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/exploiting-intermittent-fasting-to-starve-diseases-and-to-feed-autophagy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our body constructor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/03/15/learning-for-longer-and-healthier-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DNA, can break down&lt;/a&gt; every time there is a copying activity of a cell. As DNA carries our genes and provides guideline to proteins on how to build a human being, the rules it transmits are important to be correct. If the letters of the gene get mistaken, deleted, duplicated or mutated in other ways, they can be misunderstood by the proteins and incorrect outcomes may appear. For us, humans, it means getting a cancer, growing Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s or Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, and many other diseases. Our primordial “survival kit” is there to support correcting those mistakes. However, when overwhelmed with so many tasks, they lose their positions and functions and become useless at one point, even harmful. This is how we grow old and most of those diseases here or beyond mentioned are probably the symptoms of this aging process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does learning help for longer and healthier life?</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird how ignorant we are about aging or living longer. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I was questioning how I can support my body and mind to live a bit longer and in better health, or even understanding how aging works never occurred to me. Contrary to it, I always conceded that we are mortal and we mostly do not have an influence on the speed of aging. The former assumption is still valid, namely we have not yet found immortality. However, the latter thought of mine got shattered after the recent reads and researches. There is obviously a way of slightly increasing the probability of longer and healthier life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
