<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with toxic stakeholders</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/</guid>
      <description>Product development is all about finding the right problem and the adequate solution to that problem. As you can imagine, it starts with the right problem. It&amp;rsquo;s of utmost importance to identify what you are trying to find a solution for. It&amp;rsquo;s a complex and collaborative process that demands the best from all stakeholders involved.
As a Product Manager, you have to collaborate with stakeholders, regardless if you like it or not, and you do not choose how the stakeholder should behave like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on managing</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-managing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-managing/</guid>
      <description>I read an article about leading people by Adm. Hyman G. Rickover of United States Navy. The first 3 sentences were more than enough to understand the whole article.
 Human experience shows that people, not organizations or management systems, get things done. For this reason, subordinates must be given authority and responsibility early in their careers. In this way they develop quickly and can help the manager do his work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and Candor: Empowering Employees with Confidence and Trust</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re all grown-up professionals working in organizations to contribute to the success of it and advance our careers. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve undoubtedly experienced obstacles and opportunities. But what keeps us going strong is the sense of togetherness, the spirit of camaraderie, the feeling that we&amp;rsquo;re in it together, fighting the good fight, and celebrating our wins as a team. And you know what? It all boils down to one crucial thing: transparency and candor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
