<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My rating of you is a reflection of me </title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/my-rating-of-you-is-a-reflection-of-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/my-rating-of-you-is-a-reflection-of-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/&#34;&gt;Feedback&lt;/a&gt; is a necessary input to keep the motivation momentum stable and upward trending. Feedback helps people understand how their actions and behaviors impact their work and relationships. By understanding their strengths and weaknesses through feedback received, people can focus on acquiring knowledge and abilities that will help them grow personally and professionally. It encourages dialogue, clarifies expectations, and helps people work together more effectively towards common goals. When given a candid feedback, it generates a signal of trust and appreciation. How candid are the feedback though?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowing when to act</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/knowing-when-to-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/knowing-when-to-act/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An enough amount of patience is difficult to have. I want things to happen a bit faster, earlier, quicker. I even put more effort and commitment to try to make it happen as early as possible. But then it is not happening. Why?!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer is quite simple: Things take their time. Diamonds are formed within the Earth&amp;rsquo;s mantle under high pressure and temperature conditions. This process can take between 1 billion to 3.3 billion years. A butterfly goes through a transformation from an egg to a caterpillar, then to a chrysalis, and finally to a beautiful winged adult. Many high-quality wines, such as vintage ports or aged red wines, require years or even decades of aging to reach their full potential. This process allows the flavors to develop and mellow, creating a complex and delicious end product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with superstars and (hard-) rockstars</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-superstars-and-hard-rockstars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-superstars-and-hard-rockstars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of the organisations I had worked at there was a book club initiative. It was created by employees for employees. As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/finding-joy-in-the-pages-my-top-5-books-of-2022/&#34;&gt;book lover&lt;/a&gt;, I jumped into the circle. One of the books we had read was called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/29939161&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Radical Candor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Kim Scott. The book offers a guide to effective leadership and management, focusing on how to build better relationships with your team members. The core concept of Radical Candor revolves around the idea of caring personally while challenging directly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core values of a team</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/core-values-of-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/core-values-of-a-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Objectives provide the teams with a target to move towards. Core values provide them with the shared understanding of how to work together to reach the target. A set of values act like a guidance. It should be present in every interaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strong team values help to avoid conflicts, identify way of working, achieve desired results, create sense of inclusion, and have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/&#34;&gt;pyshcological safety&lt;/a&gt; at work.  For instance, if the team is valuing the customer pleasure, they will prioritize their work to increase value towards customers. Few examples of core values are the following: curiosity, empathy, customer-centricity, integrity, trust, respect, passion, developing, teamwork, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You don&#39;t understand</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/you-dont-understand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/you-dont-understand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are in a call with your manager discussing the way a critical project is moving forward. You are dealing with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/&#34;&gt;toxic stakeholder&lt;/a&gt; and you argue against the way it moves on. Then the manager respons with &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t understand&amp;rdquo;. At that point the conversation and the arguments of yours have no value against this, because you are in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.txst.edu/philosophy/resources/fallacy-definitions/straw-person.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;straw person&lt;/a&gt; fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In discussions, especially in the ones that have a disaccord of the thoughts, it is important to put a proactive commitment to actively listen. It&amp;rsquo;s significant to &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/negotiation-a-skill-to-master/&#34;&gt;understand the reasoning and the interests&lt;/a&gt; of the person you are talking to. Ask clarifying questions. If that limited time is not enough, do not make a decision on your own and do a follow up. Chiefly when you are having the thought separation with your direct reports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with toxic stakeholders</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Product development is all about finding the right problem and the adequate solution to that problem. As you can imagine, it starts with the right problem. It&amp;rsquo;s of utmost importance to identify what you are trying to find a solution for. It&amp;rsquo;s a complex and collaborative process that demands the best from all stakeholders involved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Product Manager, you have to collaborate with stakeholders, regardless if you like it or not, and you do not choose how the stakeholder should behave like. Some of them are very pleasant to work with, while some are simply a nuisance. That&amp;rsquo;s just the way it is with people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on managing</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-managing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-managing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read an &lt;a href=&#34;https://govleaders.org/rickover.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about leading people by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyman_G._Rickover&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adm. Hyman G. Rickover&lt;/a&gt; of United States Navy. The first 3 sentences were more than enough to understand the whole article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human experience shows that people, not organizations or management systems, get things done. For this reason, subordinates must be given authority and responsibility early in their careers. In this way they develop quickly and can help the manager do his work. The manager, of course, remains ultimately responsible and must accept the blame if subordinates make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and Candor: Empowering Employees with Confidence and Trust</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all grown-up professionals working in organizations to contribute to the success of it and advance our &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/&#34;&gt;careers&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve undoubtedly experienced &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/&#34;&gt;obstacles and opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. But what keeps us going strong is the sense of togetherness, the spirit of camaraderie, the feeling that we&amp;rsquo;re in it together, fighting the good fight, and celebrating our wins as a team. And you know what? It all boils down to one crucial thing: transparency and candor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
