<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>product-development on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/product-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in product-development on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/product-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Communication is overrated?!</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/communication-is-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/communication-is-overrated/</guid>
      <description>Whether building a new product, exchanging love and affection, having our day-to-day issues solved or generally pushing towards goals we have within a complex social ecosystem, communication becomes the most essential component that contributes to the success. Based on my experience as Product Owner, demands are coming from many different areas, issues happen to pop up randomly that impact and get impacted by many different fields, thus the interests and expectations of stakeholders do change because of changes to the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specializing at becoming a generalist</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</guid>
      <description>I always had this feeling that I was not good at anything. What I mean is being really good at something, being an expert, master or shihan of it. People who are experts in a specific field have always been target of my appreciation. At the same time, I feel like knowing and being capable at doing various things as well is very attractive, something I reflect about myself.
Innovation, being a critical competitive advantage, is the creative combination of various kinds of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the &#34;why&#34; of working</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</guid>
      <description>Human beings have been working since quite a long time. Even our primate ancestors worked tools out for hunting of different stones and other materials taken from the nature. So, it should not be such a new concept to reflect upon, thus let&amp;rsquo;s try it. We can put the development of working into three phases: 1) Work, 2) Job, 3) Career.
Once humans shifted from hunter-gatherer nomad bands into agrarian settlements, the design of work changed as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey on managing a product and lessons learned</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/journey-on-managing-a-product-and-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/journey-on-managing-a-product-and-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>I had a very weird dream yesterday. Inside the dream I was still in bed trying to sleep, but there were some numbers and charts flying around and screaming to me. It sounds more of a nightmare, I know. It reminds of the book, &amp;ldquo;The Phoenix Project&amp;rdquo; by Gene, Kevin and George. However, it was not like they were mad at me, but they were asking for more attention. For a moment I could understand them and put them in order for the new realm to reflect itself as a picture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
