<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nature on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Earth keeps the fire monopoly</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/earth-keeps-the-fire-monopoly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/earth-keeps-the-fire-monopoly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lighting a cigarette or a gas stove, making fire at picnic site, flaming fireworks at New Years&amp;rsquo; Eve, or heating up the fireplace is easy nowadays. Mostly we need a matchstick or a lighter. A mix of antimony sulfide, potassium chlorate, gum, and starch were all that was required to prototype a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Match&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;matchstick&lt;/a&gt; in 19. century. Around the same time was also the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C3%B6bereiner%27s_lamp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lighter&lt;/a&gt; invented.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fire, as we know it, is a chemical reaction called combustion that has three ingredients: a fuel (i.e. gasoline, wood), oxidizing agent (i.e. oxygen in the air), and heat. The combustion releases energy in the form of light and heat, and we call it flames.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survival of the Prettiest?</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/survival-of-the-prettiest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/survival-of-the-prettiest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40363053-cosmos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cosmos&lt;/a&gt; by Ann Druyan recently. I am a big fan of Carl Sagan, and this is the sequel of his blockbuster. One of the chapters talks about the plants surviving and reproducing solely via winds carrying their polens, until the insects learned to play Cupid with them. Then the evolution of relationship between flowers and insects became ever more colorful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Step into nature&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nNrieMwfpWQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rX40mBb8bkU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;theater&lt;/a&gt;, where every color, sound, and movement is part of a high-stakes performance aimed at one transcendent goal: reproduction. Here, the bowerbird doesn&amp;rsquo;t just build a nest; it creates a masterpiece, a kaleidoscope of collected treasures designed to impress. Nearby, antelopes lock horns in a show of strength, their fierce battles a testament to their desirability as mates. This is where the currency of survival is not just strength but beauty, and the art of attraction is written into every aspect of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
