<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to be a pro vacationer</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-to-be-a-pro-vacationer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-to-be-a-pro-vacationer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of us deserve a good chill at the gateway of our vacations. I personally am not a vacation-taker myself. Even if I am going abroad, I usually work from there. There are only few times a year I take weekly offs and then usually end of the year I do take a big vacation. Last time I did it was for the Christmas in 2023. I visited Georgia (the country) for 2 weeks. Such a beautiful journey to a Caucasian culture it was. I will write about that later. I did take a vacation of a week again now, but I feel that this time I did not plan my work-related handovers well enough. That&amp;rsquo;s why I am writing this article to myself and to whoever is interested about planning their vacation like a pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily doses of new deeds</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/daily-doses-of-new-deeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/daily-doses-of-new-deeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neurons that fire together, wire together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building habits has never been a strengh of mine. I find it difficult to practice consistently. Not that I do not like the activity itself, but it is quite hard for me to proactively spare time and devotion to that specific activity. I just forget it, or something else grabs my attention away from doing that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is my second day of &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/back-to-writing-hopefully-this-time-more-often/&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; in 2024. I almost forgot to write today. It is 11:30 PM while writing this piece, and I had to push myself to sit in front of the laptop and press the keys on the keyboard. It is not easy. It will be probably even harder on certain days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pareto Productivity Optimization: Achieving Your Goals More Effectively</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/pareto-productivity-optimization-achieving-your-goals-more-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/pareto-productivity-optimization-achieving-your-goals-more-effectively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was another day of &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflection&lt;/a&gt; Friday. I was looking at my annual, and quarterly targets and checking if my week was contributing to them. It has not yet been a routine for me, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/02/04/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;I try to do it every Friday&lt;/a&gt; (Tip: putting recurrent Friday blockers on a calendar helps to remind myself).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the goals I achieved in 2022 was &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2022/12/29/finding-joy-in-the-pages-my-top-5-books-of-2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reading 20 books&lt;/a&gt;. Reading helps to keep my mental health fit and learn more about the world and the people in it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/07/04/prosoche-reflecting-on-attention/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;While reviewing this goal I realized something&lt;/a&gt; does not look correct. I had read those books, but I do not remember all of them. It hit me there that reading many books does not make sense if I do not remember what I&amp;rsquo;ve read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Flappy Bird to Success in Life: How to Keep Moving Forward</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flappy Bird is a mobile game that was developed by Vietnamese video game artist and developer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dongatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dong Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;. The player must tap the screen to make the bird flap its wings and fly up, navigating through a series of pipes that appear on the screen. The goal is to fly as far as possible without hitting any pipes or the ground. Each time the bird successfully passes through a pipe, the player&amp;rsquo;s score increases. The game has simple graphics and players know it for its high level of difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making in an Uncertain World: How to Navigate the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34;&gt;You don’t know why you’re doing what you’re doing &lt;a href=&#34;#you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the company I was working at, we had a regular “Writers’ community” call where people who write blogs, and articles for a broader audience than their self get together and share their best practices, updates, new articles, etc. Participating there also led me to a workshop we had with a professional trainer, where I learned about writing articles in a structured way. As I wrote this article, I tried to use those techniques and best practices as much as possible to make the reading experience pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to ditch meetings that prevent productivity</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-to-ditch-meetings-that-prevent-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-to-ditch-meetings-that-prevent-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another meeting invite is in your inbox&amp;hellip; sigh. There are multiple reasons you probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to attend it at all: it is the only slot available for working, it is at 7 am/pm at your location, it&amp;rsquo;s at lunchtime, or you do not know what the meeting is about. This gives me a real déjà vu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are all going through this turmoil after remote working became a must, thanks to (or more like damn) COVID. We had to in such a short period adjust to not being in the office, but still learning to deliver outcomes as we were doing before. It was neither an expected nor a planned event for the global economy and human beings themselves. However, it is estimated that around 25% of the global workforce will stay remote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychology of Remote Working and 16 tips to make it work</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote working will more likely stay in long term. If not hundred percent, it will definitely push many companies to adopt hybrid model. With the COVID hit, tens of millions of people had to move their workplaces to their living places, to their homes. In multiple studies (mostly by management consulting companies) it is estimated that more than 20 to 25 percent of the workforce could work three to five days a week remotely. Obviously, the remote work at the moment is possible for only the people whose work does not require physical output. There are many dimensions impacted by workforce going remote, such as counter-urbanization, &amp;ldquo;to-go&amp;rdquo; delivery vs. restaurants, commercial real-estate and so on. These are all business-side changes, however there is as well a direct impact of remote working on human psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prosochē - Reflecting on attention</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/prosoch%C4%93-reflecting-on-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/prosoch%C4%93-reflecting-on-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult for me to put my attention onto one thing and keep it there for long time. I am getting distracted very easily from the incoming e-mail, a call, the feeling of hunger, the beeping sound of the Whatsapp and so many other stuff. While trying to formulate my thoughts into reasonable structure I shortly went on Clubhouse to listen to some friends and it took me twenty minutes to get back to the activity of writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling lazy today and it&#39;s fine</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to get this article published on Monday, but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish it before midnight. Instead I just read some articles, listened to some discussions on ClubHouse and slowly started writing. It&amp;rsquo;s not very usual for me in last half a year to take things easy and become lazy whenever I feel like it. That&amp;rsquo;s when questioning kicked in. Why is laziness seen as evil?! Is it really a bad thing to be lazy?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on making mistakes</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-making-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-making-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mistakes are perceived as potential threats. It&amp;rsquo;s the fear of vulnerability to existential threats in the harsh world that feeds our mind with the avoidance mechanism against making mistakes. However, yielding too much to this fear of vulnerability hits us with another destructive outcome: seeking perfectionism at all costs. Perfectionism such a delusional will that can turn us into petty-minded, judgmental and unhappy person that we try to avoid originally. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if making mistakes is really bad or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed Gratification - is it even worth it?!</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/delayed-gratification-is-it-even-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/delayed-gratification-is-it-even-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to give out something now for a return that we&amp;rsquo;ll get at a later point. We want an immediate pleasure and evolutionary it has been central for our survival. Food, water, sex, and more food were necessary to keep up living and pass on our genes to the next generation. We did not have to care about anything else so much. However, with the dynamics of modern world and as we age, for a greater purpose in mind we are learning to endure the lack of immediate pleasure - delayed gratification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does learning help for longer and healthier life?</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird how ignorant we are about aging or living longer. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I was questioning how I can support my body and mind to live a bit longer and in better health, or even understanding how aging works never occurred to me. Contrary to it, I always conceded that we are mortal and we mostly do not have an influence on the speed of aging. The former assumption is still valid, namely we have not yet found immortality. However, the latter thought of mine got shattered after the recent reads and researches. There is obviously a way of slightly increasing the probability of longer and healthier life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the &#34;why&#34; of working</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human beings have been working since quite a long time. Even our primate ancestors worked tools out for hunting of different stones and other materials taken from the nature. So, it should not be such a new concept to reflect upon, thus let&amp;rsquo;s try it. We can put the development of working into three phases: 1) Work, 2) Job, 3) Career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once humans shifted from hunter-gatherer nomad bands into &lt;a href=&#34;https://heyhido.com/posts/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/&#34;&gt;agrarian settlements&lt;/a&gt;, the design of work changed as well. It was the first time some collective tasks formed and hierarchies of labor emerged, thanks to private property. For quite a long time this work modus operandi continued. Only in the last couple of centuries the idea of &amp;ldquo;job&amp;rdquo; showed up. The main differentiating characteristic of job from work is the professional image. If it was only physical labor that was needed before, now we have a job where we can manage some machinery, which requires a basic qualification we need to amass. Yet very infant, the &amp;ldquo;career&amp;rdquo; concept is what we are living now with. People are not working just to earn money anymore, but rather as well improve their qualifications to move to the next step of their professional growth ladder. Thus the organisations have more difficulty to get their employees stick with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on sleeping and learning</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-sleeping-and-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/reflecting-on-sleeping-and-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sleeping less than six hours a day increases the risk of having certain forms of cancer, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, inconsistency of blood sugar, blockage of coronary arteries, psychiatric diseases such as depression, anxiety, suicidality, obesity and some other things. Sleep keeps our body&amp;rsquo;s metabolic state in balance by fine-tuning the insulin and circulating glucose. A good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep makes sure our gut microbiome is nutritionally plentiful, as well as our brain is refreshing itself. How is this biologically dumb-looking process important for our survival? I mean, we cannot gather/eat food, we cannot reproduce, we cannot socialize, we cannot protect ourselves and beloved ones while sleeping, because in sleep our all muscles are paralysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullet-proof productivity with OKRs</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in late 1970s Andy Grove, in Intel, introduced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2O3spbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OKR (Objectives &amp;amp; Key Results)&lt;/a&gt;, inspired by Peter Drucker&amp;rsquo;s MBO (Management by Objective) method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatmatters.com/faqs/okr-meaning-definition-example/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OKR&lt;/a&gt; is a goal-setting method used to define strategic goals and measurable results used by organizations. OKRs help to build a direction and prioritized focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of today there are many companies who have adopted OKRs as their growth compass. The organisation I am currently working at has been also using OKRs since couple of years. When I heard about the concept, it caught my attention right away. It was both simple and easy, two things you can hardly see together. After doing some research and reading the book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2O3spbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Measure What Matters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by John Doerr, I decided to experiment it for my personal development and the result is just incredible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
