<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Hido</title>
    <link>https://heyhido.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heyhido.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Wild Ride with AI in 2024: A Slightly Frazzled Reflection</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/my-wild-ride-with-ai-in-2024-a-slightly-frazzled-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/my-wild-ride-with-ai-in-2024-a-slightly-frazzled-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been 9 months since I have written anything here, but yeah folks, buckle up because I&amp;rsquo;m about to take you on a rollercoaster ride through my 2024 AI adventure. And let me tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s been one heck of a journey!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first: if you&amp;rsquo;re not already blown away by the AI revolution happening right under our noses, it&amp;rsquo;s time to wake up and smell the silicon! This tech is so powerful, it makes my old iPod look like a fancy paperweight with a dysfunctional scroll wheel. (Remember frantically spinning that wheel to find your favorite song? Ah, simpler times!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacking 1s and 0s via physics</title>
      <link>https://heyhido.com/posts/hacking-1s-and-0s-via-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heyhido.com/posts/hacking-1s-and-0s-via-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a very interesting &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AaZ_RSt0KP8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Veritasium video&lt;/a&gt; on Tiktok today. It talks about how cosmic rays, high-energy particles from space, have been discovered to cause rare yet impactful phenomena on Earth. From triggering bit flips in computer systems to potentially influencing glitches in video games, the effects of cosmic rays are pervasive in modern technology. These rays can do unintended acceleration in vehicles and crashes of supercomputers at high elevations, highlighting the significant role they play in disrupting our technological systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
