<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Hido</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dual consciousness - how the left hemisphere owns the brain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dual-consciousness-how-the-left-hemisphere-owns-the-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dual-consciousness-how-the-left-hemisphere-owns-the-brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brain is such a complex mechanism. Over last few centuries the science went so far that we could go explore the depth of universe, understand the initial big-bang event, analyze the black-hole and many more wonders spanning billions of light years. After the Cambrian explosion, some 500 million years ago, [invention of photosynthesis by the Cyanobacteria]http://localhost:1313/posts/beginning-of-oxygen/ led to the sudden blossoming of complex forms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From unicellular organisms to us with central nervous system, the development requires a more sophisticated ways of thinking to understand - memory, imagination, processing science and so forth. However, we have a very limited understanding of how the brain works. I read an article about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adam-mehdi.medium.com/dual-consciousness-and-the-split-brain-6558751edfb3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Split-brain&lt;/a&gt; that opened up my curiosity and after some reading here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running an enablement session</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-an-enablement-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-an-enablement-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/enablement-as-part-of-a-product/&#34;&gt;Rolling out enablement&lt;/a&gt; as part of a product release ensures the usage is smooth and seamless. There are multiple ways one can integrate enablement into user experience. This post will focus on running an enablement session within organisation. Enablement sessions are crucial for sharing knowledge, aligning product features, gathering feedback, growing the skills of users which adds to the innovative culture of the ogranisation. Running an effective enablement session requires careful planning and execution. There are several key strategies to ensure your enablement sessions are engaging, informative, and valuable for all participants. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of them in detail:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am forgetful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-am-forgetful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-am-forgetful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some tricky interview questions you hear when applying for jobs. One of the most famous is &amp;ldquo;What are your weaknesses?&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think many people answer it honestly. It is important to find a diplomatically correct answer before this question gets answered. Nevertheless, if someone would ask me what my biggest weakness is, and assuming I&amp;rsquo;d answer it honestly, the answer is &amp;ldquo;I am forgetful&amp;rdquo;. I do forget things easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can bullshit a bullshitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-bullshit-a-bullshitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-bullshit-a-bullshitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bullshit &lt;a href=&#34;https://uwaterloo.ca/news/media/research-shows-people-who-bs-are-more-likely-fall-bs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;is defined&lt;/a&gt; as information designed to impress, persuade, or otherwise mislead people that is often constructed without concern for the truth. At its core, it reflects a fundamental aspect of human communication: the desire to influence others and shape a perception.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From psychology point of view, social norms and cultural values can very much influence one&amp;rsquo;s propensity to engage in bullshitting. In environments where success and status are highly valued, individuals may choose bullshitting to fit to the group. Also people with fragile self-esteem or those who are overly concerned with their image may resort to &amp;ldquo;bullshitting&amp;rdquo; as a way to maintain or enhance their social standing. This behavior can be a defense mechanism to protect one&amp;rsquo;s self-image or to project an idealized version of oneself to others. This creates a discrepancy between one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs and actions, which is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_dissonance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cognitive dissonance&lt;/a&gt;. To reduce the feeling of discomfort the cognitive dissonance creates, individuals may engage in dishonest behavior, I mean bullshitting, rationalizing it in a way that aligns with their self-perception or goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My rating of you is a reflection of me </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-rating-of-you-is-a-reflection-of-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-rating-of-you-is-a-reflection-of-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/&#34;&gt;Feedback&lt;/a&gt; is a necessary input to keep the motivation momentum stable and upward trending. Feedback helps people understand how their actions and behaviors impact their work and relationships. By understanding their strengths and weaknesses through feedback received, people can focus on acquiring knowledge and abilities that will help them grow personally and professionally. It encourages dialogue, clarifies expectations, and helps people work together more effectively towards common goals. When given a candid feedback, it generates a signal of trust and appreciation. How candid are the feedback though?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Oops, I Did It Again&#39; - reflecting on self-control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oops-i-did-it-again-reflecting-on-self-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oops-i-did-it-again-reflecting-on-self-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am doing a regular &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/exploiting-intermittent-fasting-to-starve-diseases-and-to-feed-autophagy/&#34;&gt;intermittent fasting&lt;/a&gt; since years. My regular fasting cycle is 18h-6h, but there are days where I go 22h-2h, or even 23h-1h. I even do days of dry fasting, namely neither food nor liquid intake. It can sound to some as quite unhealthy, which for some is indeed unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have colleagues who can calmly navigate a day full of deadlines, crises, and last-minute meetings without breaking a sweat. Some of my friends, despite a hectic schedule, always find time for the gym, meal prepping, and even a side hustle. What&amp;rsquo;s the secret? I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is an superhuman power - it is self-control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enablement as part of a product</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/enablement-as-part-of-a-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/enablement-as-part-of-a-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had few experiences already with software, or a hardware that I tried to use, but stopped after few moments of interacting with it. Main reason has always been &amp;ldquo;not knowing how to use&amp;rdquo;. When something is not working easily, I usually give up using it. I am one of those, yes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data products, such as reports or data analysis, require more cognitive load to understand and use. Main purpose of using data products is to extract insights from them and apply to optimize the business processes. Certain visual representation of a specific metric over a dimension can ease the understanding, but in a report where multiple metrics and views are presented can become complex.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never-ending noteapp.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-noteapp.txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-noteapp.txt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping a to-do list is already quite difficult. Moving between apps, getting the todos done, adding new ones, organizing them. Setting up the setup itself can easily derail me from doing the actual, thing, the todo itself. Now I have a more or less consistent way of taking care of my todos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While reading a book yesterday, I wanted to write a note from the book. I did have no place to do it. I quickly searched for dusty memory pieces of mine about where I used to write my daily stuff. I have used few techniques in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make the decision and do not regret</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-the-decision-and-do-not-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-the-decision-and-do-not-regret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are certain times in life that you face the difficulty of making a decision. You know what I am talking about, right?! Those decisions that make you feel uncomfortable. Those are the ones that keep you awake at the night, or just get into your dreams and haunt you there as well. Those are the ones where you know that one of them will definitely make you better off (possible also to be worse off) and the other won&amp;rsquo;t, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know which one it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core values of a team</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/core-values-of-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/core-values-of-a-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Objectives provide the teams with a target to move towards. Core values provide them with the shared understanding of how to work together to reach the target. A set of values act like a guidance. It should be present in every interaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strong team values help to avoid conflicts, identify way of working, achieve desired results, create sense of inclusion, and have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/&#34;&gt;pyshcological safety&lt;/a&gt; at work.  For instance, if the team is valuing the customer pleasure, they will prioritize their work to increase value towards customers. Few examples of core values are the following: curiosity, empathy, customer-centricity, integrity, trust, respect, passion, developing, teamwork, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You don&#39;t understand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-dont-understand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-dont-understand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are in a call with your manager discussing the way a critical project is moving forward. You are dealing with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/dealing-with-toxic-stakeholders/&#34;&gt;toxic stakeholder&lt;/a&gt; and you argue against the way it moves on. Then the manager respons with &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t understand&amp;rdquo;. At that point the conversation and the arguments of yours have no value against this, because you are in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.txst.edu/philosophy/resources/fallacy-definitions/straw-person.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;straw person&lt;/a&gt; fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In discussions, especially in the ones that have a disaccord of the thoughts, it is important to put a proactive commitment to actively listen. It&amp;rsquo;s significant to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/negotiation-a-skill-to-master/&#34;&gt;understand the reasoning and the interests&lt;/a&gt; of the person you are talking to. Ask clarifying questions. If that limited time is not enough, do not make a decision on your own and do a follow up. Chiefly when you are having the thought separation with your direct reports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courage as a skill to grow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/courage-as-a-skill-to-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/courage-as-a-skill-to-grow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/courage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the Cambridge Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;, courage is the ability to control your fear in a dangerous or difficult situation. Let&amp;rsquo;s analyse this definition word-by-word to see what courage is about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Courage is &lt;strong&gt;an ability&lt;/strong&gt;. Ability is having the skill or a proficiency to do something. In this case, courage is not an inherent trait, but rather a skill to learn. As with every skill, it is something one can grow by learning and practicing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never-ending todo lists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-todo-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-todo-lists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping to-dos helps to organize and create focus for the given limited time period. There are many tasks that flow in non-stop. Some of those tasks are to be done urgently, some are important but not urgent, some are &amp;ldquo;waiting&amp;rdquo; tasks, some are to be delegated, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As it is quite an important and an easy-to-excel-at skill to have, there are many tools that try to provide people with this magic power. My favorites are &lt;a href=&#34;https://asana.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;. Not going to mention the reasons, maybe in another post I can do that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dead sunday</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dead-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dead-sunday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With few friends I have a Sunday routine of visiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panorama-therme.de/startseite/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;thermal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://caracalla.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;baths&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the few activities that keeps me look forward for Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Going to Baden-Baden Caracalla thermal bath, we did do a short city tour and had a coffee at a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hotel-beek.de/cafe-patisserie-restaurant/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;patisserie&lt;/a&gt;, and an amazing dinner at a &lt;a href=&#34;https://restaurant-nani.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;georgian restaurant&lt;/a&gt;. All good, all nice, we are happy. Then one of my friends mentioned that the city is empty. There is no one at the city centre, it&amp;rsquo;s all quite. Feels deserted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fostering workplace camaraderie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fostering-workplace-camaraderie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fostering-workplace-camaraderie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Socializing is part of human nature, historically. In an earlier post I have talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/&#34;&gt;the &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; of working&lt;/a&gt;. The evolution of work can be divided into three stages: Work, Job, and Career. Initially, as humans transitioned from nomadic hunter-gatherers to agrarian societies, collective tasks and labor hierarchies emerged, transforming the nature of work. In recent centuries, the concept of a &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo; developed, characterized by the professional image and the need for basic qualifications to operate machinery. The most recent phase, the &amp;lsquo;career,&amp;rsquo; reflects a shift where people work not just for money but for professional growth, making it harder for organizations to retain employees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and Candor: Empowering Employees with Confidence and Trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transparency-and-candor-empowering-employees-with-confidence-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all grown-up professionals working in organizations to contribute to the success of it and advance our &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/&#34;&gt;careers&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve undoubtedly experienced &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/&#34;&gt;obstacles and opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. But what keeps us going strong is the sense of togetherness, the spirit of camaraderie, the feeling that we&amp;rsquo;re in it together, fighting the good fight, and celebrating our wins as a team. And you know what? It all boils down to one crucial thing: transparency and candor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making in an Uncertain World: How to Navigate the Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34;&gt;You don’t know why you’re doing what you’re doing &lt;a href=&#34;#you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the company I was working at, we had a regular “Writers’ community” call where people who write blogs, and articles for a broader audience than their self get together and share their best practices, updates, new articles, etc. Participating there also led me to a workshop we had with a professional trainer, where I learned about writing articles in a structured way. As I wrote this article, I tried to use those techniques and best practices as much as possible to make the reading experience pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping sanity with Home Office in COVID times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-sanity-with-home-office-in-covid-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-sanity-with-home-office-in-covid-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the vaccination process slightly boosting, some advanced economies are opening up slowly. City centers begin to get crowded, eating at restaurants sounds exciting and social life blossoms again. Some of us are even scared that people create the risk of a new wave with their careless attitude.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was definitely a difficult year and &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/25/the-uncomfortable-truth-about-hope/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;full of uncertainty&lt;/a&gt; for everyone and still is. The quarantine period fed us with &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/23/reflecting-on-obstacles-resilience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;various stressors&lt;/a&gt; that made the process of social distancing even more unbearable. During the long lock-down periods we developed feelings of anger, PTSD and phobic avoidance behaviors. The concern of infecting our beloved ones made us stick to isolation. The economic downgrade increased the fear of losing our job. Sense of loneliness, demoralization, boredom, fear, anxiety and depression has become a new normal for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does our brain tell us about habits?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big part of our life is, without us consciously thinking about it, occupied with habitual processes, such as eating 3 meals a day (breakfast, lunch and dinner&amp;hellip; all at specific hours of day), sleeping (due to our circardian rythym), working (9am-5pm), and so on. We do not question these habits, neither do we have difficulty in remembering to do them, nor do we feel like not doing them. It is sort of automatic and instinctive. Habits let us do things automatically without thinking. This &amp;rsquo;not thinking&amp;rsquo; part should be, obviously, inherent to our brain. What does our brain do about habits?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
