<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-Development on Hido</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/self-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-Development on Hido</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/self-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily doses of new deeds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/daily-doses-of-new-deeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/daily-doses-of-new-deeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neurons that fire together, wire together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building habits has never been a strengh of mine. I find it difficult to practice consistently. Not that I do not like the activity itself, but it is quite hard for me to proactively spare time and devotion to that specific activity. I just forget it, or something else grabs my attention away from doing that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is my second day of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/back-to-writing-hopefully-this-time-more-often/&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; in 2024. I almost forgot to write today. It is 11:30 PM while writing this piece, and I had to push myself to sit in front of the laptop and press the keys on the keyboard. It is not easy. It will be probably even harder on certain days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pareto Productivity Optimization: Achieving Your Goals More Effectively</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pareto-productivity-optimization-achieving-your-goals-more-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pareto-productivity-optimization-achieving-your-goals-more-effectively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was another day of &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflection&lt;/a&gt; Friday. I was looking at my annual, and quarterly targets and checking if my week was contributing to them. It has not yet been a routine for me, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/02/04/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;I try to do it every Friday&lt;/a&gt; (Tip: putting recurrent Friday blockers on a calendar helps to remind myself).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the goals I achieved in 2022 was &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2022/12/29/finding-joy-in-the-pages-my-top-5-books-of-2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reading 20 books&lt;/a&gt;. Reading helps to keep my mental health fit and learn more about the world and the people in it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/07/04/prosoche-reflecting-on-attention/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;While reviewing this goal I realized something&lt;/a&gt; does not look correct. I had read those books, but I do not remember all of them. It hit me there that reading many books does not make sense if I do not remember what I&amp;rsquo;ve read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Flappy Bird to Success in Life: How to Keep Moving Forward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/from-flappy-bird-to-success-in-life-how-to-keep-moving-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flappy Bird is a mobile game that was developed by Vietnamese video game artist and developer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dongatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dong Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;. The player must tap the screen to make the bird flap its wings and fly up, navigating through a series of pipes that appear on the screen. The goal is to fly as far as possible without hitting any pipes or the ground. Each time the bird successfully passes through a pipe, the player&amp;rsquo;s score increases. The game has simple graphics and players know it for its high level of difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making in an Uncertain World: How to Navigate the Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-making-in-an-uncertain-world-how-to-navigate-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34;&gt;You don’t know why you’re doing what you’re doing &lt;a href=&#34;#you-dont-know-why-youre-doing-what-youre-doing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the company I was working at, we had a regular “Writers’ community” call where people who write blogs, and articles for a broader audience than their self get together and share their best practices, updates, new articles, etc. Participating there also led me to a workshop we had with a professional trainer, where I learned about writing articles in a structured way. As I wrote this article, I tried to use those techniques and best practices as much as possible to make the reading experience pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Joy in the Pages: My Top 5 Books of 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/finding-joy-in-the-pages-my-top-5-books-of-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/finding-joy-in-the-pages-my-top-5-books-of-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is an amazing activity that has many benefits for the mind, body, and soul. Not only does it expand your knowledge and understanding of the world, but it also improves your vocabulary and language skills, can improve your memory and concentration, and can even reduce stress and improve mental health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who are not regular readers, it might be easy to underestimate the power of reading and the impact it can have on your life. But for those who make reading a regular part of their routine, the benefits are multiple and far-reaching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to ditch meetings that prevent productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-ditch-meetings-that-prevent-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-ditch-meetings-that-prevent-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another meeting invite is in your inbox&amp;hellip; sigh. There are multiple reasons you probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to attend it at all: it is the only slot available for working, it is at 7 am/pm at your location, it&amp;rsquo;s at lunchtime, or you do not know what the meeting is about. This gives me a real déjà vu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are all going through this turmoil after remote working became a must, thanks to (or more like damn) COVID. We had to in such a short period adjust to not being in the office, but still learning to deliver outcomes as we were doing before. It was neither an expected nor a planned event for the global economy and human beings themselves. However, it is estimated that around 25% of the global workforce will stay remote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychology of Remote Working and 16 tips to make it work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology-of-remote-working-and-16-tips-to-make-it-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote working will more likely stay in long term. If not hundred percent, it will definitely push many companies to adopt hybrid model. With the COVID hit, tens of millions of people had to move their workplaces to their living places, to their homes. In multiple studies (mostly by management consulting companies) it is estimated that more than 20 to 25 percent of the workforce could work three to five days a week remotely. Obviously, the remote work at the moment is possible for only the people whose work does not require physical output. There are many dimensions impacted by workforce going remote, such as counter-urbanization, &amp;ldquo;to-go&amp;rdquo; delivery vs. restaurants, commercial real-estate and so on. These are all business-side changes, however there is as well a direct impact of remote working on human psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prosochē - Reflecting on attention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/prosoch%C4%93-reflecting-on-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/prosoch%C4%93-reflecting-on-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult for me to put my attention onto one thing and keep it there for long time. I am getting distracted very easily from the incoming e-mail, a call, the feeling of hunger, the beeping sound of the Whatsapp and so many other stuff. While trying to formulate my thoughts into reasonable structure I shortly went on Clubhouse to listen to some friends and it took me twenty minutes to get back to the activity of writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/seeking-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/seeking-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are busy living our lives. You know, the life that has a typical pattern of being born, school, fun, career, family, and death. We&amp;rsquo;re so constantly distracted that we do not have time to &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;communicate with ourselves&lt;/a&gt;. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/05/19/mindful-listening-why-is-it-so-difficult-and-what-can-we-do-about-it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;attention span shrank due to the&lt;/a&gt; amount of info we are processing, we run away from pain and &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/06/21/meaningful-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;crave for only happiness&lt;/a&gt;, we judge people so easily without filtering our thoughts or judgements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just shortly put everything aside and connect with ourselves, put our attention to our body, feelings, emotions and perceptions. Once we can connect and communicate with ourselves, it is easier to communicate with others as well. One main reason is that when we connect with ourselves, we see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/28/reflecting-on-the-point-of-living/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;suffering inside&lt;/a&gt;. If we are able to understand and take care of this inner suffering, in our communication with others we do realise that they most likely have their own sufferings and thus creates the empathy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/meaningful-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/meaningful-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of days ago I saw two videos (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CZJvBfoHDk0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;1,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=74SN33t3bwA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) that made me go through the topic of living a happy life again. Actually, not really a happy life but rather a meaningful life (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eudaimonia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eudaimonia&lt;/a&gt;), because the happiness is somehow attached to pleasure (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hedonia&lt;/a&gt;) and can be a misleading word if not used within the specific context. I should admit that it is not very easy to pinpoint specific checklist or features of a meaningful life, but stoics have defined a meaningful life as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication is overrated?!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-overrated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/02/22/my-journey-on-managing-a-product-and-lessons-learned/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;building a new product&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/04/12/power-of-love-and-expectations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;exchanging love and affection&lt;/a&gt;, having our &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/23/reflecting-on-obstacles-resilience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;day-to-day issues solved&lt;/a&gt; or generally &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/02/01/reflecting-on-passion-and-perseverance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pushing towards goals&lt;/a&gt; we have within a &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/12/negotiation-a-skill-to-master/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;complex social ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;, communication becomes the most essential component that contributes to the success. Based on my experience as Product Owner, demands are coming from many different areas, issues happen to pop up randomly that impact and get impacted by many different fields, thus the interests and expectations of stakeholders do change because of changes to the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping sanity with Home Office in COVID times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-sanity-with-home-office-in-covid-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-sanity-with-home-office-in-covid-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the vaccination process slightly boosting, some advanced economies are opening up slowly. City centers begin to get crowded, eating at restaurants sounds exciting and social life blossoms again. Some of us are even scared that people create the risk of a new wave with their careless attitude.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was definitely a difficult year and &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/25/the-uncomfortable-truth-about-hope/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;full of uncertainty&lt;/a&gt; for everyone and still is. The quarantine period fed us with &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/23/reflecting-on-obstacles-resilience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;various stressors&lt;/a&gt; that made the process of social distancing even more unbearable. During the long lock-down periods we developed feelings of anger, PTSD and phobic avoidance behaviors. The concern of infecting our beloved ones made us stick to isolation. The economic downgrade increased the fear of losing our job. Sense of loneliness, demoralization, boredom, fear, anxiety and depression has become a new normal for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindful Listening - why is it so difficult and what can we do about it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mindful-listening-why-is-it-so-difficult-and-what-can-we-do-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mindful-listening-why-is-it-so-difficult-and-what-can-we-do-about-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the start of the COVID lock-down, we&amp;rsquo;ve realized the importance of social interaction even more. Given all the talking and listening, we usually think that we are good listeners. In reality, most of us are very bad at listening, remembering only 25-50 percent of what our hearing senses transmit. Just to make the point clear, at most, on average, only the half of what people tell us we listen to and perceive, the rest we just hear. It does not necessarily mean that we do not care about the people we talk to, but we simply cannot grasp it all. Instead, we daydream about different issue, we tend to formulate responses and try to push our ideas before knowing the whole point the other person tries to make.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration vs Exploitation. Which way to go?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploration-vs-exploitation.-which-way-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploration-vs-exploitation.-which-way-to-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all trying to keep our lives in place. As we grow older, it becomes more important to cultivate some more stability and less risk, partially due to extra responsibilities we get from our surrounding and from the system itself. There is a observable transition from child&amp;rsquo;s irresponsible wandering to adult&amp;rsquo;s tediously planned next steps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We actually have a very extended childhood compared to our hominins. Chimpanzees already become self-sufficient around 7 years old, whereas for humans it starts at least around the age of 15 (nowadays in most countries full time working age is accepted to start at 16). Homosapiens adults are obliged to feed &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/04/12/power-of-love-and-expectations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;and protect their children&lt;/a&gt; until they can do it themselves independently. Thus they need to make sure their child&amp;rsquo;s every next step is planned to be safe. Child then is completely free to do what it wants, thanks to the parents. With the contraction of protection and feeding from the parents as the child grows older, the young one limits the risk of extincting due to random and dangerous acts such as petting a crocodile or going with a stranger to buy an ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specializing at becoming a generalist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/specializing-at-becoming-a-generalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always had this feeling that I was not good at anything. What I mean is being really good at something, being an expert, master or shihan of it. People who are experts in a specific field have always been target of my appreciation. At the same time, I feel like knowing and being capable at doing various things as well is very attractive, something I &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflect about myself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Innovation, being a critical competitive advantage, is the creative combination of various kinds of knowledge. To bring up innovation, the breadth of the knowledge and expertise base should be large enough. On top of that, these compounds should have a bonding feature which that is a general applicable type within the various shapes and sizes of input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling lazy today and it&#39;s fine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feeling-lazy-today-and-its-fine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to get this article published on Monday, but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish it before midnight. Instead I just read some articles, listened to some discussions on ClubHouse and slowly started writing. It&amp;rsquo;s not very usual for me in last half a year to take things easy and become lazy whenever I feel like it. That&amp;rsquo;s when questioning kicked in. Why is laziness seen as evil?! Is it really a bad thing to be lazy?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trust and Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-and-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-and-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a very fundamental level, trust is a bonding mechanism in social interactions. Without it we would not have exchanged any products with each other, let states protect us, be socially proactive, or fall in &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/04/12/power-of-love-and-expectations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;love&lt;/a&gt;. Trust is such an important feeling that makes us open up our vulnerabilities and weaknesses to people whom &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/25/the-uncomfortable-truth-about-hope/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;we have no control over&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On an evolutionary timeline, once shifting from nomad bands to &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/02/15/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;agrarian settlements&lt;/a&gt; we started to bond together with the same group of people over long-term. Protecting the settlements, cultivating food, hunting, and trading cross-settlements required trust among these civilizations. As we have been betrayed a lot throughout history, we also have built up the self-defense mechanism that keeps the trust at a smart level. The hormone called oxytocin (OT) motivates us to be trustworthy by boosting our empathy for others. Basically, if you treat me well, I will have oxytocin in my brain extracted and synthesized, combined with the impact on my central and peripheral nervous system as well, I will be motivated to reciprocate voluntarily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power of Love and Expectations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/power-of-love-and-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/power-of-love-and-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If, as two strangers, we suddenly let our guards down, open our vulnerabilities to each other, feel close and give in to each other, we live the moment of the most exhilarating and exciting experience of our lives. Our hearts pound, our eyes become bigger, we cannot sit quiet, and arbitrary thoughts occupy the cognitive capacity. We listen to our song, remember those moments, try to visualize the eyes, the voice, but only blurred and miss being together. These two feelings, falling in love and separation, changes so much in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on making mistakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-making-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-making-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mistakes are perceived as potential threats. It&amp;rsquo;s the fear of vulnerability to existential threats in the harsh world that feeds our mind with the avoidance mechanism against making mistakes. However, yielding too much to this fear of vulnerability hits us with another destructive outcome: seeking perfectionism at all costs. Perfectionism such a delusional will that can turn us into petty-minded, judgmental and unhappy person that we try to avoid originally. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if making mistakes is really bad or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed Gratification - is it even worth it?!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/delayed-gratification-is-it-even-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/delayed-gratification-is-it-even-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to give out something now for a return that we&amp;rsquo;ll get at a later point. We want an immediate pleasure and evolutionary it has been central for our survival. Food, water, sex, and more food were necessary to keep up living and pass on our genes to the next generation. We did not have to care about anything else so much. However, with the dynamics of modern world and as we age, for a greater purpose in mind we are learning to endure the lack of immediate pleasure - delayed gratification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Intermittent Fasting to starve diseases and to feed Autophagy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploiting-intermittent-fasting-to-starve-diseases-and-to-feed-autophagy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploiting-intermittent-fasting-to-starve-diseases-and-to-feed-autophagy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our body constructor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/03/15/learning-for-longer-and-healthier-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DNA, can break down&lt;/a&gt; every time there is a copying activity of a cell. As DNA carries our genes and provides guideline to proteins on how to build a human being, the rules it transmits are important to be correct. If the letters of the gene get mistaken, deleted, duplicated or mutated in other ways, they can be misunderstood by the proteins and incorrect outcomes may appear. For us, humans, it means getting a cancer, growing Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s or Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, and many other diseases. Our primordial “survival kit” is there to support correcting those mistakes. However, when overwhelmed with so many tasks, they lose their positions and functions and become useless at one point, even harmful. This is how we grow old and most of those diseases here or beyond mentioned are probably the symptoms of this aging process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does learning help for longer and healthier life?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-does-learning-help-for-longer-and-healthier-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird how ignorant we are about aging or living longer. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I was questioning how I can support my body and mind to live a bit longer and in better health, or even understanding how aging works never occurred to me. Contrary to it, I always conceded that we are mortal and we mostly do not have an influence on the speed of aging. The former assumption is still valid, namely we have not yet found immortality. However, the latter thought of mine got shattered after the recent reads and researches. There is obviously a way of slightly increasing the probability of longer and healthier life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the &#34;why&#34; of working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-the-why-of-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human beings have been working since quite a long time. Even our primate ancestors worked tools out for hunting of different stones and other materials taken from the nature. So, it should not be such a new concept to reflect upon, thus let&amp;rsquo;s try it. We can put the development of working into three phases: 1) Work, 2) Job, 3) Career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once humans shifted from hunter-gatherer nomad bands into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/&#34;&gt;agrarian settlements&lt;/a&gt;, the design of work changed as well. It was the first time some collective tasks formed and hierarchies of labor emerged, thanks to private property. For quite a long time this work modus operandi continued. Only in the last couple of centuries the idea of &amp;ldquo;job&amp;rdquo; showed up. The main differentiating characteristic of job from work is the professional image. If it was only physical labor that was needed before, now we have a job where we can manage some machinery, which requires a basic qualification we need to amass. Yet very infant, the &amp;ldquo;career&amp;rdquo; concept is what we are living now with. People are not working just to earn money anymore, but rather as well improve their qualifications to move to the next step of their professional growth ladder. Thus the organisations have more difficulty to get their employees stick with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on why we get angry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-why-we-get-angry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-why-we-get-angry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anger is present everywhere around us. If we would like to sum the occasions of us getting angry throughout the day, we may need someone else to lend us their fingers as well to support counting. The situations that spark anger can range from being very trivial to an emotionally significant level, mostly being trivial though. This feeling turns off our reasoning capacity and relies on the judgment of the fire that we feel inside ourselves and does not care about any consequences, at least not at the very moment of its peak heat. Moreover, the fury, if not cooled down, can be ongoing for some time. So, what is the problem? Isn&amp;rsquo;t anger a normal thing? If not, then why do we feel it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Investing and Wealthy Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-investing-and-wealthy-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Neolithic Revolution, around 12,000 years ago, several nomadic bands shifted from being hunter-gatherers to larger agrarian settlements. Along with this shift, communities started to establish private property rights, as well store and exchange value. The latter one brought us to invent money, turn it into a virtual value and speculate based on ignorance and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the rise of globalisation and consumerism, money became the central part of our lives. Moving from just being an exchange tool, money turned into an addiction. We can see it in financial markets. People are losing their minds over gambling in trading markets. Nonetheless, when done correctly investing brings us a financial independence, which frees us from many non-value-adding troubles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on sleeping and learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-sleeping-and-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-sleeping-and-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sleeping less than six hours a day increases the risk of having certain forms of cancer, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, inconsistency of blood sugar, blockage of coronary arteries, psychiatric diseases such as depression, anxiety, suicidality, obesity and some other things. Sleep keeps our body&amp;rsquo;s metabolic state in balance by fine-tuning the insulin and circulating glucose. A good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep makes sure our gut microbiome is nutritionally plentiful, as well as our brain is refreshing itself. How is this biologically dumb-looking process important for our survival? I mean, we cannot gather/eat food, we cannot reproduce, we cannot socialize, we cannot protect ourselves and beloved ones while sleeping, because in sleep our all muscles are paralysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullet-proof productivity with OKRs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bullet-proof-productivity-with-okrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in late 1970s Andy Grove, in Intel, introduced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2O3spbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OKR (Objectives &amp;amp; Key Results)&lt;/a&gt;, inspired by Peter Drucker&amp;rsquo;s MBO (Management by Objective) method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatmatters.com/faqs/okr-meaning-definition-example/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OKR&lt;/a&gt; is a goal-setting method used to define strategic goals and measurable results used by organizations. OKRs help to build a direction and prioritized focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of today there are many companies who have adopted OKRs as their growth compass. The organisation I am currently working at has been also using OKRs since couple of years. When I heard about the concept, it caught my attention right away. It was both simple and easy, two things you can hardly see together. After doing some research and reading the book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2O3spbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Measure What Matters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by John Doerr, I decided to experiment it for my personal development and the result is just incredible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on Passion and Perseverance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-passion-and-perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflecting-on-passion-and-perseverance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2021/01/04/how-self-reflection-leads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-reflection&lt;/a&gt; is a vital activity for steering a good life. It helps us understand ourselves, control out attitude towards life, build resilience to adversities and make solid plans. There is also another important point to understand: there is no meaning on what we do in the future. Whether we work in a company, get married and have children or we build a business empire and control the world. The end is: we all will die and, most likely, never come back or remember anything of this life. So, what&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/28/reflecting-on-the-point-of-living/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;point of living&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://heydaroff.info/2020/12/28/reflecting-on-the-point-of-living/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hoping&lt;/a&gt; about future?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does our brain tell us about habits?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-does-our-brain-tell-us-about-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big part of our life is, without us consciously thinking about it, occupied with habitual processes, such as eating 3 meals a day (breakfast, lunch and dinner&amp;hellip; all at specific hours of day), sleeping (due to our circardian rythym), working (9am-5pm), and so on. We do not question these habits, neither do we have difficulty in remembering to do them, nor do we feel like not doing them. It is sort of automatic and instinctive. Habits let us do things automatically without thinking. This &amp;rsquo;not thinking&amp;rsquo; part should be, obviously, inherent to our brain. What does our brain do about habits?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negotiation - a skill to master</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/negotiation-a-skill-to-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/negotiation-a-skill-to-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Negotiation is about extracting maximum value depending on persuading the other party to allow or not block it. Usually the negotiations are considered to be a battle where one party wins and the other party loses. This fighting nature of ours is coming from the long history of human survival and is encoded in our genes. In evolutionary terms, fighting is assumed to be the surest route to survival and increased reproduction, achieving status and belonging. In negotiating, it is a very similar approach that we use to gain what we want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
